https://www.sacap.edu.za/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
SACAP Privacy Policy
DEFINITIONS AND INTERPRETATION“Board” means the board of directors of SACAP.“Personal Information” means information relating to an identifiable, living, natural person and where it is applicable, identifiable, existing juristic person, including all information as defined in POPI.“POPI” means the Protection of Personal Information Act 4 of 2013.“SACAP Community” includes SACAP students, employees, contractual educators, consultants and suppliers.“SACAP” means the South African College of Applied Psychology (Pty) Limited.
SCOPESACAP respects the privacy of the SACAP community. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to set out SACAP’s information collecting and processing practices, in compliance with POPI.This Privacy Policy governs the collecting and processing of Personal Information provided to SACAP by the SACAP community.Due to legal and other developments, SACAP may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time and at any time. The version of the terms and conditions effective for this Privacy Policy are indicated by the effective date incorporated in the title of this Privacy Policy. The date indicated in the heading of this Privacy Policy is the effective date that governs the application of this Privacy Policy from that date until the next revision of this Privacy Policy becomes effective.This Privacy Policy applies to electronic, multimedia and hardcopy records in all formats created, received, managed, stored, retained and disposed by SACAP. Such records include all institutional, commercial and technical records relevant to the work of SACAP.
PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATIONSACAP will only collect and/or process the Personal Information of persons who have consented to such collection and/or processing.In collecting and/or processing Personal Information:
SACAP will only collect and/or process Personal Information for a purpose consistent with the purpose for which such Personal Information is required. The specific purpose for which Personal Information is
collected and/or processed will be lawful and such purpose will be apparent from the context in which the Personal Information is requested.SACAP will only collect and/or process Personal Information in a manner that is adequate, relevant and not excessive in the context of the purpose for which it is collected and/or processed.Personal Information will only be processed for a purpose compatible with that for which it was collected, unless you have agreed to an alternative purpose in writing
or SACAP is permitted to do so in terms of national legislation of general application dealing primarily with the protection of Personal Information. SACAP will keep records of all Personal Information collected as well as the specific purpose for which it was collected, for a period of 1 (one) year from the date on which such Personal Information was last used or SACAP is required, by law, to keep such records for a longer period of time.SACAP will not disclose any person’s Personal Information to any third party, unless such person, whose Personal Information is so requested, has provided SACAP with prior written consent to do so or SACAP is required, by law, to disclose such information to a third party.Where SACAP has obtained consent to disclose any person’s Personal Information to any third party, SACAP will retain a record of the Personal Information so disclosed. Such record shall include, the third party to which the Personal Information was disclosed, the reason for such disclosure and the date of such disclosure. This record shall be kept by SACAP for a period of 1 (one) year from the date on which the Personal Information was disclosed or SACAP is required, by law, to keep such records for a longer period of time.SACAP will destroy or delete any Personal Information that is no longer required by SACAP for the purpose it was initially collected, or subsequently processed.
RECORDS MANAGEMENTThe implementation of this policy is assigned to the office of the records manager (“the Records Manager”).Save as where otherwise resolved by the Board, SACAP’s managing director shall serve, ex officio, as the Records Manager.The Records Manager shall take reasonable measures to ensure that Personal Information is identified, classified, retained, stored, protected and disposed of in such a manner that its integrity is not compromised and that unlawful access to or dissemination of such Personal Information is prevented.Notwithstanding the aforegoing, neither SACAP nor the Records Manager, shall be liable under any circumstances for any loss or damage sustained as a result of unlawful access to or dissemination of any Personal Information.
